Guide to the Richard Kelly Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional papers, 1909-1978; Series II
  - Lighting
    - Middletown Manufacturing, orders and inquiries regarding lights designed by Kelly, 1950-1958 (Box 410, Folder 32)
    - Photographs, Circa 1950s, undated (Box 410, Folder 33-34)
    - Sketch book, Circa 1951 (Box 410, Folder 35)
    - Sketches, Undated (Box 410, Folder 36)
  - Lumen Award Program, 1978 (Box 410, Folder 37)
  - Materials and fixtures index, Circa 1960s (Box 345, Folder 6)
  - Materials data and samples, 1957-1970 (Box 345, Folder 7-10)
  - Notes, 1963-1972 (Box 410, Folder 38)
  - Notes on lighting, 1962-1963 (Box 345, Folder 11)
  - Office day sheets, 1950-1952 (Box 345, Folder 12-14)
  - Office day sheets, 1953-1965 (Box 346, Folder 1-13)
  - Office records
    - Client list, 1964-1965 (Box 410, Folder 39)
    - Client list card file, with billing information, 1936-1964 (Box 425)
    - Employee and client policy, 1941-1965 (Box 347, Folder 1)
    - Job applicants, 1962-1966 (Box 347, Folder 2)
    - Job lists
      - 1951 (Box 347, Folder 3)
      - 1961-1963 (Box 410, Folder 40)
    - Office contacts and telephone numbers, 1962-1963 (Box 347, Folder 4)
    - Office meeting, minutes, 1960 November 1 (Box 410, Folder 41)
    - Office stationery, Circa 1960s (Box 347, Folder 5)
  - Patent
    - Chandelier, 1956 October 30 (Box 410, Folder 42)
    - 1957 (Box 347, Folder 6)
  - Periodicals
    - General, 1927-1964 (Box 347, Folder 7-12)
    - General, 1965-1971 (Box 348, Folder 1-2)
    - BLBS News, 1967 December (Box 410, Folder 43)
    - Oversize (Box 394, Folder 1)
  - Photographic materials
    - Negatives, unidentified, Undated (Box 410, Folder 44)
    - Photographs
      - 1909-1950 (Box 348, Folder 3-11)
      - 1955-1958, undated (Box 410, Folder 45-46)
      - Undated (Box 412, Folder 9)
    - Slides, glass, Undated
      Slides are unlabeled and undated. Many depict architectural lighting projects on which Richard Kelly worked, as well as miscellaneous images. There were project and subject label markers which had been dislodged from their positions before the materials were received by Manuscripts and Archives; the markers were retained in box 410, folder 47.
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 417)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 418)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 419)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 420)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 421)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 422)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 423)
      - Unidentified, Undated (Box 424)
    - Slides, glass, identification labels, Undated (Box 410, Folder 47)
    - Slides, unidentified, Undated (Box 410, Folder 48)
  - Press (A), 1956-1964
    - General (Box 349, Folder 1-14)
    - Oversize (Box 394, Folder 2)
  - Press (B-V)
    - General
      - 1947-1971 (Box 350, Folder 1-21)
      - 1955-1964 (Box 412, Folder 10-13)
    - Oversize, 1950-1958 (Box 394, Folder 3-5)
  - Professional engagements
    - Building Research Institute (BRI) Building Lighting Committee, 1962 (Box 411, Folder 1)
    - Columbia University, 1956-1968 (Box 351, Folder 1)
    - Columbia University, 1959-1969 (Box 351, Folder 2-4)
    - Columbia University, Arch 6063Y, 1968 April (Box 411, Folder 2)
    - Flowering Plant Societies of New York, 1972 May (Box 411, Folder 3)
    - Garden Club of America, 1962-1963 (Box 411, Folder 4)
    - Graham Foundation, 1958 (Box 351, Folder 5)
    - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1952 (Box 411, Folder 5)
    - Illuminating Engineering Society (IES)
      - 1953-1976 (Box 351, Folder 6-12)
      - 1958-1979 (Box 411, Folder 6-7)
    - Indoor Light Gardening Society of America (ILGSA), 1970-1974 (Box 411, Folder 8-9)
    - Industrial Home for the Blind, 1972 (Box 352, Folder 1)
    - International Association of Lighting Designers (IALD), 1976 (Box 352, Folder 2)
    - Inter-Society Color Council, 1952-1963 (Box 352, Folder 3-5)
    - Longwood Gardens, 1973 (Box 411, Folder 10)
    - Municipal Art Society, 1963 (Box 352, Folder 6)
    - Nat's Communication Inc., 1969 (Box 352, Folder 7)
    - National Home Fashions League, 1955 (Box 352, Folder 8)
    - National Residential Lighting Contest, Sylvania, 1963 (Box 411, Folder 11)
    - National Society of Interior Designers, 1968-1969 (Box 411, Folder 12)
    - New Jersey Society of Architects, 1962 (Box 352, Folder 9)
    - New York University, 1952 April 3 (Box 411, Folder 13)
    - North Carolina State College, 1958 (Box 352, Folder 10)
    - Parsons School of Design, 1976 (Box 352, Folder 11)
    - Pratt Institute, 1961 (Box 352, Folder 12)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1951-1954 (Box 411, Folder 14)
    - Spanish Institute, Inc.
      - 1965 (Box 352, Folder 13)
      - 1967 February (Box 411, Folder 15)
    - Syracuse University, 1959 (Box 352, Folder 14)
    - Texas Society of Architects, 1968 (Box 411, Folder 16)
    - University of Houston, 1959 (Box 352, Folder 15)
    - University of Nebraska, 1962 (Box 352, Folder 16)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1973 (Box 352, Folder 17-19)
    - University of Toronto, 1960-1964 (Box 352, Folder 20)
    - Western Reserve University, 1961-1962 (Box 411, Folder 17)
    - Yale University
      - 1942-1943 (Box 352, Folder 21)
      - 1963-1976 (Box 411, Folder 18-20)
    - Zanesville Art Institute, Undated (Box 411, Folder 21)
  - Prospective jobs, 1958-1963 (Box 352, Folder 22)
  - Public relations, 1961-1962 (Box 352, Folder 23)
  - Reference material
    - 1961-1967, undated (Box 411, Folder 22-24)
    - 1932-1964, undated (Box 412, Folder 14)
  - Speeches by contemporaries, 1963-1971 (Box 353, Folder 1)
  - Weekly agenda, 1945-1965 (Box 353, Folder 2-5)
  - Writings
    - "A Home of One's Own", 1946 (Box 353, Folder 6)
    - "The Better to See," House and Garden, 1946 December (Box 411, Folder 25)
    - "Choosing the Right Light for Your Plants," The Designer, 1971 (Box 411, Folder 26)
    - College Art Journal, 1952 (Box 353, Folder 7)
    - "Design Journal: Private Lighting," Interior Design and Decoration, 1949 July (Box 411, Folder 27)
    - Drafts, unidentified, Undated (Box 411, Folder 28-29)
    - Fuel Oil Journal, 1934 September (Box 411, Folder 30)
    - "A Home of Your Own for Perfect Living", 1948 (Box 411, Folder 31)
      Book prospectus.
    - "How to Light Your Paintings," House and Garden, 1947 January (Box 411, Folder 32)
    - Lectures and papers, 1951-1962 (Box 353, Folder 8)
    - "Light Story", 1946 (Box 411, Folder 33)
    - "Lighting Is Architecture," Progressive Architecture, 1958 September (Box 411, Folder 34)
    - "Making the Most of Lighting," New York Times, 1948 October 3 (Box 411, Folder 35)
    - Manuscript for Lightolier Co., 1957 (Box 353, Folder 9)
    - "The Meaning of Light in Architectural Design", 1953 February 26 (Box 411, Folder 36)
    - Modern Primitive Architecture, 1947 (Box 353, Folder 10)
    - Museum News, 1959 (Box 411, Folder 37)
    - New Decade, 1960 (Box 353, Folder 11)
    - Notes, 1944-1969 (Box 353, Folder 12)
    - Notes, costume design, 1969 (Box 353, Folder 13)
    - Preliminary drafts, 1956 (Box 353, Folder 14-16)
    - "Sales Control Through Engineered Lighting Effects," Women's Wear Daily, 1950 February 15 (Box 411, Folder 38)
    - "Subliminal Store Lighting Can Create Positive Reaction Among Customers", 1958 (Box 412, Folder 15)
- Personal papers, 1925-1981; Series III
  - Affiliations and memberships
    - First School of Dada
      - Circa 1937 (Box 354, Folder 1)
      - 1937 (Box 426, Folder 16)
    - James Joyce Society
      - 1960-1968 (Box 354, Folder 2)
      - 1970-1973 (Box 426, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-1967 (Box 354, Folder 3)
  - Blank postcards, 1948-1967 (Box 354, Folder 4)
  - Brochures, 1942-1972 (Box 354, Folder 5-6)
  - Christmas greetings
    - 1938-1957 (Box 354, Folder 7)
    - 1940, 1965 (Box 426, Folder 1)
  - Clippings
    - Architecture and planning, 1944-1964 (Box 354, Folder 8)
    - Arts and culture, 1939-1981 (Box 354, Folder 9-10)
    - Ceremonial, landmark events, 1943-1962 (Box 354, Folder 11)
    - Entertainment, 1939-1953 (Box 354, Folder 12)
    - Furniture and lamps, 1950-1964 (Box 354, Folder 13)
    - Illumination, revolutionary houses, 1944-1966 (Box 355, Folder 1)
    - Interior lighting conditions, 1944-1966 (Box 355, Folder 2)
    - Lifestyle, 1939-1960
      - General (Box 355, Folder 3-4)
      - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 1)
    - Lighting
      - Exhibits, paintings, Undated (Box 426, Folder 2-3)
      - Television, farms, gas, electroluminescence, 1952-1961 (Box 355, Folder 5)
    - Notes and typography, 1964 (Box 355, Folder 6)
    - Political, 1967 (Box 355, Folder 7)
    - Stationery and memorabilia, 1957-1971 (Box 355, Folder 8-9)
    - World War II years, 1939-1942 (Box 355, Folder 10)
  - Columbia University
    - Student work, 1932 (Box 355, Folder 11-13)
    - Student work, including Columbia Jester, Circa 1932 (Box 428, Folder 1)
    - Student life, 1932, 1937 (Box 426, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence
    - 1936-1974 (Box 356, Folder 1-9)
    - 1947-1977, undated (Box 426, Folder 6-10)
  - Entertainment and activities
    - 1941-1971 (Box 426, Folder 11-14, Box 357, Folder 1-2)
    - 1959-1965 (Box 426, Folder 11-14)
  - Event announcements and invitations, 1939-1972 (Box 357, Folder 3-4)
  - Event programs, 1949-1957 (Box 357, Folder 5)
  - Family, general, 1958, undated (Box 426, Folder 15)
  - Notes and pieces, 1931-1948, undated (Box 426, Folder 18)
  - Obituary, 1977 July 4 (Box 426, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, Circa 1950s (Box 357, Folder 6)
  - Playbills, 1937-1953 (Box 357, Folder 7)
  - School work, Circa 1932-1945, undated
    Some of the items in these folders have not been definitively identified as student work.
    - General
      - Circa 1932-1945 (Box 428, Folder 3)
      - Undated (Box 426, Folder 20-21)
    - Architectural drawings, Circa 1932-1945 (Box 428, Folder 4-5)
    - Graphic designs, sketches, watercolor, Circa 1932-1945 (Box 429, Folder 1)
    - Lighting, Circa 1932-1945 (Box 428, Folder 2)
    - Room mock-ups (Box 427, Folder 1-4)
  - Sketches and renderings, 1925-1943
    - General (Box 357, Folder 8-10)
    - Oversize (Box 395, Folder 2)
  - Wedding vows, Undated (Box 426, Folder 22)
  - Yale University
    - Coursework
      - Circa 1942-1943 (Box 426, Folder 23-25)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 357, Folder 11)
    - Drawings
      - 1943 (Box 357, Folder 12-13)
      - Circa 1945 (Box 428, Folder 6)